<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<resource xmlns='http://datacite.org/schema/kernel-3' xmlns:xsi='http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance' xsi:schemaLocation='http://datacite.org/schema/kernel-3 http://schema.datacite.org/meta/kernel-3/metadata.xsd'>
  <identifier identifierType='DOI'>10.14749/1407399498</identifier>
  <creators>
    <creator>
      <creatorName>Zuma, Khangelani</creatorName>
    </creator>
    <creator>
      <creatorName>Human Sciences Research Council</creatorName>
    </creator>
  </creators>
  <titles>
    <title xml:lang='en'>HSRC Master Sample II</title>
  </titles>
  <publisher>HSRC - Human Science Research Council SA</publisher>
  <publicationYear>2014</publicationYear>
  <contributors>
    <contributor contributorType='Distributor'>
      <contributorName>Human Sciences Research Council</contributorName>
    </contributor>
    <contributor contributorType='Funder'>
      <contributorName>Human Sciences Research Council</contributorName>
    </contributor>
    <contributor contributorType='RightsHolder'>
      <contributorName>Human Sciences Research Council</contributorName>
    </contributor>
  </contributors>
  <language>eng</language>
  <resourceType resourceTypeGeneral='Dataset'/>
  <version>1.0</version>
  <rightsList>
    <rights>
      By accessing the data, you give assurance that The data and documentation
      will not be duplicated, redistributed or sold without prior approval from
      the rights holder. The data will be used for scientific research or
      educational purposes only. The data will only be used for the specified
      purpose. If it is used for another purpose the additional purpose will be
      registered. Redundant data files will be destroyed. The confidentiality of
      individuals/organisations in the data will be preserved at all times. No
      attempt will be made to obtain or derive information from the data to
      identify individuals/organisations. The HSRC will be acknowledged in all
      published and unpublished works based on the data according to the
      provided citation. The HSRC will be informed of any books, articles,
      conference papers, theses, dissertations, reports or other publications
      resulting from work based in whole or in part on the data and
      documentation. For archiving and bibliographic purposes an electronic copy
      of all reports and publications based on the requested data will be sent
      to the HSRC. To offer for deposit into the HSRC Data Collection any new
      data sets which have been derived from or which have been created by the
      combination of the data supplied with other data. The data team bears no
      responsibility for use of the data or for interpretations or inferences
      based upon such uses. Failure to comply with the End User License may
      result in sanctions being imposed.
    </rights>
  </rightsList>
  <descriptions>
    <description descriptionType='Abstract' xml:lang='en'>
      &lt;p&gt; The 2005 HSRC Master Sample was used for SABSSM 2008 and 2012,
      the SANHANES study in 2012 and SASAS 2007-2010 (adjacent EAs) to obtain an
      understanding of geographical spread of HIV/AIDS, perceptions and
      attitudes of people and other health related studies over time.&lt;/p&gt;
    </description>
    <description descriptionType='Abstract' xml:lang='en'>
      &lt;p&gt; A sample can be defined as a subset containing the
      characteristics of a larger population. Samples are used in statistical
      testing when population sizes are too large for the test to include all
      possible members or observations. A sample should represent the whole
      population and not reflect bias toward a specific attribute.[1]&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;p&gt; One of the most crucial aspects of sample design in household
      surveys is its frame. The sampling frame has significant implications on
      the cost and the quality of any survey, household or
      otherwise.[2]&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; The sampling frame .... in a household
      survey must cover the entire target population. When that frame is used
      for multiple surveys or multiple rounds of the same survey it is known as
      a master sample frame or .... master sample.[3]&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; A
      master sample is a sample drawn from a population for use on a number of
      future occasions, so as to avoid ad hoc sampling on each occasion.
      Sometimes the master sample is large and subsequent inquiries are based on
      a sub-sample from it.[4]&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; The HSRC compiles master
      samples in order to construct samples for various HSRC research studies.
      The 2005 HSRC Master Sample was used for SABSSM 2008 and 2012, SASAS
      2007-2010 and the SANHANES study in 2012 to obtain an understanding of
      geographical spread of HIV/AIDS, perceptions and attitudes of people and
      other health related studies over time.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; The 2005 HSRC
      Master Sample was created in the following way:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; South
      Africa was delineated into EAs according to municipality and province.
      Municipal boundaries were obtained from the Municipal Demarcation Board.
      An Enumeration area (EA) is the smallest geographical unit (piece of land)
      into which the country is divided for census or survey enumeration.[5] The
      concepts and definitions of terms used for Census 2001 comply in most
      instances with United Nations standards for censuses.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;
      A total of 1,000 census enumeration areas (EAs) from the 2001 population
      census were randomly selected using probability proportional to size and
      stratified by province, locality type and race in urban areas from a
      database of 80 787 EAs that were mapped using aerial photography to
      develop an HSRC master sample for selecting households.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;p&gt; The ideal frame would be complete with respect to the target
      population if all of its members (the universe) are covered by the
      frame.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; Ideal characteristics of a master
      sample:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt; The master frame should be as
      complete, accurate and current as practicable.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt; A
      master sample frame for household surveys is typically developed from the
      most recent census, just as a regular sample frame is.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt; Because the master frame may be used during an entire
      intercensal (between census) period, however, it will usually require
      periodic and regular updating such as every 2-3 years.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt; This is in contrast to a regular frame which is more likely to
      be up-dated on an ad hoc basis and only when a particular survey is being
      planned[6]&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;p&gt; [1]
      http://www.investopedia.com/terms/s/sample.asp&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; [2]
      http://unstats.un.org/unsd/demographic/meetings/egm/sampling_1203/docs/no_3.pdf&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; [3] http://unstats.un.org/unsd/demographic/meetings/egm/sampling_1203/docs/no_3.pdf&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; [4] A Dictionary of Statistical Terms, 5th edition, prepared for the International Statistical Institute by F.H.C. Marriott. Published for the International Statistical Institute by Longman Scientific and Technical. http://stats.oecd.org/glossary/detail.asp?ID=3708&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; [5] http://africageodownloads.info/128_mokgokolo.pdf&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; [6] http://unstats.un.org/unsd/demographic/meetings/egm/sampling_1203/docs/no_3.pdf&lt;/p&gt;
    </description>
  </descriptions>
  <geoLocations>
    <geoLocation>
      <geoLocationPlace> National - all 9 provinces</geoLocationPlace>
    </geoLocation>
  </geoLocations>
</resource>
